Guide to the John D. Krumboltz Papers SC0219
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John D. Krumboltz papers
1937-2015
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Krumboltz, John D.
SC0219
160 Linear Feet
Primarily professional correspondence and papers relating to his activities at Stanford and his work on national committees in the field of education; topics range from vocational education and career skills to human relations training and behavioral modification. Also includes departmental office files.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Professor John Krumboltz, 1979-2016.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of education and psychology at Stanford (1961- ).
Description of the Collection
Primarily professional correspondence and papers relating to his activities at Stanford and his work on national committees in the field of education; topics range from vocational education and career skills to human relations training and behavioral modification. Also includes departmental office files.
Educational psychology.; Krumboltz, John D.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education. Faculty; Krumboltz, John D.; Krumboltz, John D.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1992-148
  - Research projects and proposals, 1980-89 (Personal responsibility; bicultural competence; occupation attraction) (Box 1)
  - Notes for book "Cognitive View of Career Development," London, 1983-84 (Box 2)
  - Career Belief Inventory (CBI) Printouts – Reliability, Factor analysis, Item analysis (Box 3)
  - CBI answer sheets from sites 000 – 404 (Box 4)
  - CBI answer sheets from sites 405 – 411 (Box 5)
  - Personal Responsibility Study from Study of Stanford and the Schools – raw data, reports (Box 5)
  - Personal Responsibility Study from Study of Stanford and the Schools – raw data, reports (Box 6)
  - Psych. Studies Committee, 1966-85 (Box 6)
  - CPSE 1989-92 (Box 6)
  - SII, MBTI, FIRO-B raw data from CCEC (for correlation with CBI) (Box 6B)
  - CBI statistical analysis (Box 6B)
  - CBI background and development materials (Box 6B)
  - CBI background and development materials (Box 7)
  - CBI reliability printouts (Box 7)
  - CBI answer sheets from sites 101-117, 944-948, 956-959 (Box 7)
  - Career Counseling courses, 1969-88 (Box 8)
  - Course materials, 1961-79 (Research Tech. and Behavior Modification) (Box 9)
  - Love letters to uncle Orus Krumboltz, 1934-38 (from Althea) (Box 9)
  - Counseling course materials, 1963-72 (Box 10)
  - Speeches 1967-91 (Box 10)
  - Writing Projects, 1963-72 (Box 11)
  - Decision Quality Position papers (Box 11)
  - Personal Responsibility Project (Box 12)
  - Study of Stanford and the Schools, 1982-85 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1985-92; letters of recommendation; McDaniel Foundation; competency exams; administration of counseling psych; job experience kits (Box 13)
  - Counseling courses, 1965-87 (Box 14)
  - Former students and associates, 1985-88 (Box 15)
  - Stanford committees, 1980-91 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous articles CPSE 1985 (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous articles CPSE 1985 (Box 18)
  - CBI answer sheets from sites 960 - 980 (Box 18)
  - CBI answer sheets from sites 981 – 999 (Box 19)
  - Stanford committees, 1984-91 (Box 19)
  - Computer data tapes (5 reels):
    - Krumboltz/Nichols/Ford. Stanford in the Schools. Personal Responsibility Pros. (Box 20)
    - JDK 196. IBM SL 6250 BPI 84 files, 3/27/92 (Box 20)
    - Krumboltz. Data from USOE sponsored research: "The Effect of Alternative CDM (?) on the quality of Resulting Decisions 1977-1979" (Box 20)
    - Rude, Stephanie. CERAS Building. Modified seqdata file with demographics (Box 20)
    - Krumboltz. USOE Study on CDM 1977-79 (Box 20)
- Additional Papers, Accessio ARCH-2016-137
  - Administrative files
  - Teaching files
    - ED 131/Psych 152, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Career and Personal counseling in culturally diverse settings, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Ed 234, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Peer counselling techniques, 1996 Fall (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Ed 193A, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Ed 480, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Dispute resolution training institute 40 hour meditation course, 2002 Jun (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Behavior systems training program, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Administration of Coun. Psych. Program, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Administration of Coun. Psych program, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Answering machine manual (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Budget Reduction, 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Budget statements, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Child Abuse reporting (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Coaching as Learning (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Competencies (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Competencies + Exam Policy, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Consulting Professor Appointments (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Copyright and patent agreement Stanford University (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - CACREP Standards, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - C.P. Billet, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Counseling Program Rescue, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - School counseling, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Counseling Films, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Eric (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Evaluation of Counseling Outcomes (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Evaluation of CP Program, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Fax (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Financial statements, 1992-2004 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Follow-up interviews + grads, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Funding sources (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Frequently asked questions: new program (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Fund raising, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Future of Coun. Psych. Comm, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - "Future of C.P. Report, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Graduate education in psychology (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - History of California Counseling, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Internship information (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Internship application advice (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Job opportunities (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - McDaniel Foundation, 2013-2014 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Professional Organizations, Committees, Conferences
    - Journal of Career Assessment, 2001 Jun 18 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Local Career Development Group (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - National Career Education Leaders' Communication Network, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - NCDA Brain Trust 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - NCDA- Career developments (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - NCDA conference, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - NCDA Convention, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - NCDA Convention, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - NCDA Convention, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - NCDA Convention, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - NCDA Convention, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Professional colleagues in England, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Society for Scientific Exploration, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Western Psychological Association, 2005 Apr (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - CPPC Advisory Board, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Policy on Postdoctoral visitors, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Faculty club (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - part-time C.P. Pos, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - C.P. faculty search, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Activity Credit Issue, 1994 May-Jun (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Benefits at Stanford (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - CEP, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Stanford School of Education By-laws, 1985-2004 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - classroom improvement (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Conflict of Interest policy, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Consulting Professors committee, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Cross-disciplinary seminar, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Cubberly Library Report, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - External review of the School of Education, 1996 Jan (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - F grades letter, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Faculty policy on Conflict of Commitment and Interest (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Faculty retreat, 2000 Oct 27 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Graduate special Ph.D committee, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Health behavior education MA program, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Honors Program, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Honors, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Honors program evaluation (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Innovation in Technology and Education (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Jane Stanford (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Judicial Affairs, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - LaFromboise promotion (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Learning, Design, + Technology, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Longevity center (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Lotan, Rachel (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Carl E. Thoresen (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Multicultural, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Multimedia faculty position (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Research Training Grant Committee, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Retirement Committee, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - sexual harrassment advisors, 2009 Oct 14 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Spencer Grant, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Stanford Center on Adolescence, 1997 Mar-Jul (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - SUSE Mission statement, 1996 Jan (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Wineberg, S. S./McGraw, L. L. A Follow-up Study of Graduates of Stanford's Psychological Studies in Education: a Preliminary Report (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Wineberg, S. S./McGraw, L. L. A Follow-up Study of Graduates of Stanford's Psychological Studies in Education: a Preliminary Report (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Career hopes (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Job Experience Kit - computer programmer (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Career simulation research course (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Multimedia job experience (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Research: Career simulation (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Selection of Occupations: OccSim (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Script: advertising (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Hooper, Judith Make-believe takes off, 1986 Jan (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Ad prototype reviews (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Multi-media job simulation (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Occupational simulations (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - ACES Natl. Task force on Career Development, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Association for Advancement of Behavior Therapy, 1981-1992 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - AACD Convention, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - AACD Convention, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - AACD Convention, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - AACD Convention, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Association for Counselor Education and Supervision, 2002 Fall (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - ACA Convention, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - ACA Convention, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - ACPA Convention, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - AERA Div. E (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - AERA Special Interest Group on a Career Education-Career Guidance (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - AERA Convention, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - AERA Convention, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - AERA Convention, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - AERA Convention, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - AERA Convention, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - AERA Convention, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - AERA Convention, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - AERA Convention, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - AERA Convention, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - AERA Convention, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - APA Division 5, 2009 Oct (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Division 15 - APA, 2009 Jun (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Div. 17, 1988-89 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Society for Vocational psych Div. 17 of APA, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Div. 17 Therapy Outcome Section, 2004 May (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Div. 17 Past Presidents Council, 1999 Feb 8 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - APA Division 25, 2000 Spring (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Div. 45 APA, 2003 Spring (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Voc. Psych sig. conf. Ohio, 1994 May (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - APA Convention, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - APA Convention, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - APA Convention, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - APA Convention, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - APA Convention, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - APA Convention, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - APA Convention, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - APA Convention, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - APA Convention, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - APA Convention, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - APA Convention, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - APA Convention, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - APA Convention, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - APA Convention, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - APA Convention, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - APA Convention, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - APA Convention, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - APA Convention, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - APA Division 17 -- Special interest group training programs in school of education (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - American Psychological Society, 1996 Jan (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - California Political Action, 1998 Apr (Box 23, Folder 52)
    - CACD Convention, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 53)
    - California Career Development Association, 2007 (Box 23, Folder 54)
    - California Career Conference, 1989 Nov (Box 23, Folder 55)
    - California Career Conference, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 56)
    - California Career Conference, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 57)
    - California Career Conference, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 58)
    - California Career Conference, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 59)
    - California Career Conference, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 60)
    - California Career Conference, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 61)
    - California Career Conference, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 62)
    - California Career Conference, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 63)
    - California Career Conference, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 64)
    - California Career Conference, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 65)
    - CACES, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 66)
    - California Psychological Association (Box 23, Folder 67)
    - CCA compass, 2007 (Box 23, Folder 68)
    - Chi Sigma Iota, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 69)
    - Council of Counseling Psychology Training Programs (Box 23, Folder 70)
    - Coun. Psych national conference, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 71)
    - Educational Research Journal, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 72)
    - Flat Earth society (Box 23, Folder 73)
    - International Association for Educational and vocational guidance, 2004 Jan (Box 23, Folder 74)
    - CAMECD (Box 23, Folder 75)
    - ICDC, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 76)
  - Speeches, Writing, Consulting
    - Graduate education (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Future role of Coan psych (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - CBI workshop, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - School-to-Work transition (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Encouraging Researchers (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Transparencies: Soc. Learning Theory, Careers (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Career counseling in 21st century (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Exercises: CBI workshop (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Competitive grading (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "Brilliant Insights-- platitudes that bear repeating" (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Metaphors in counseling, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Occupationism (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Korea, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Korea, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Australia, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Speech: IACMP, 1999 Jul 8 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Speech: Spain, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Speech: Canada, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Hong Kong, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Speech, MACCA, Pennsylvania, 2002 Oct (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Speech Italy, 2001 Oct-2003 December (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Speech New Hampshire, 2000 Apr (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Coe College, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Speech: Alberta, Canada, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Speech: CACD, LA, 2001 Feb 24 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Japan consulting + speech, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Speech New Zealand, 2001 Nov (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - NYCA, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - NCDA San Francisco, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - New Jersey, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Mind garden (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - MacTaggart Novel (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Mindsteps, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Mindfruit (Ryan Babineux) (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Waterman, Judy (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - WASC Accreditation (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - VA Advisory Board: CWT (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Video on CDM: Jon Carlson (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Speaker arrangements, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Springboard (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - 1991 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - New Zealand (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - PAUSD Career program, 1989 Mar (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - myroad.com (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Licensure of counselors, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Lead International - UAE, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Italy (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Immigration, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - IBM at Career action center, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - H.O.P.E project (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Grass Valley Group (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Graduate psychology education program, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Germany (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Geropsychology grants, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Fun 2 try next (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Encounter Software, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - University of Hawaii, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Necessity of College by Education Level, 1992-1995 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - AIM Speech, Chicago, 1991 Sep (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings: "Love Learning", 1989 Jul (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Advice that sticks, 1987 Feb 11 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Ferrero, G.W., Lungstrom, R.M., McKenna, A.E. Ninth grade students' attitudes toward nontraditional occupations. Paper presented at AERA, San Francisco, 1989 Mar 28 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Jaeger, R., Tesh, A. Professional satisfaction and dissatisfaction among practicing counselors: Implications for counselor education (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Speech, 1965 Nov (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Krumboltz: "Thinking, Feeling, and Behaving" intl journal for the advancement of counselling (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Thinking, feeling, behaving (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Stories (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Cartoon transparencies (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Publishing agreements: assessing career development, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Possible book publishers, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Royalty reports, assessing career development, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Autobiography, 1980 Mar (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Babineaux Book (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - "Beliefs about work"… Australian Journal of career development (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Career assessment and soc learning theory with Margo Jackson, 1993 Jun (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Career Beliefs of School counselors - MS Thompson + Coon (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Case studies book - Al Levin (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - CBI by Age Margo (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Career + relationship similarities: Allen (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Author's release form, 1974 Jun 24 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Community vs. 4 year colleges - Coon (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - DSM 1.0 Diagnostic strengths (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - C.P. in educ.: replies, 1988 Oct 24 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Ranieri Krumboltz "culture day" (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Hallum Krumboltz "Parents … disabled" (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Goals of education, 1999 Aug (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Jackson + Krumboltz "Career Practicum", 1998 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Goals of education (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Counselor in training: ethnic sensitivity (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Counseling psychology as an educational specialty, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - CP: cover your base (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - CP: cover your base transparencies (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Place of C.P. in education - MS (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - CP in education: feedback from draft, 1989 Apr (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Encouraging research, 2000 Nov 14 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Encyclopedia of Career Dev, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Encyclopedia of Education, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Greg Book, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Gore "Computer Competencies", 2001 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Happenstance Learning theory, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Henderson: Social Learning Theory, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - High school psych, teacher article, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Interview - J. Counseling Dev., 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Hallum/Krumboltz. "Parents of Young Adult-age children with severe disabilities" (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Graham, Dawn Thesis, 2007 Aug (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Krumboltz Evaluating Models of Career Choice, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Needed research in guidance, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Permissions to reprint, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Peterson + Krumboltz "Career", 2000-2002 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "Positive Psych" Cary Watson (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Professional issues Chan, 2004 Sep- December (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Professionalism (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Quality of life with AIDS Vosvick (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Scroll, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Permission to use copyright material (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Positive psychology, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - School counseling article (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Strong, Agrest: "C.P. in 21st century, 1999 Sep (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "Wisdom of Indecision" Art. J. of Voc. Beh, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Yearn, Learn, and Earn Ranieri, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - video ratings, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Krumboltz + Yeh "Grading Policy", 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Practicum record form, 1989 Spring (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Practicum record form, 1988 Fall (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Practicum record form, 1989 Winter (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Practicum record form, 1989 Winter (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Transparencies "learning to love learning" (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Transparencies: "Learning to love learning" (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Graphic masters: "Learning to love learning" (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Occupational attraction (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Video: cog. Restructuring (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Speech: Prison Chaplains, Sacramento, 1988 Jun 21-22 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Speech, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Speech (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Patterson Debate (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "Accountability in Counseling" (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "What schools should teach but don't" (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Speech + transparencies: Changing Children's behavior (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Krumboltz "A Second Look at the Revolution in Counseling" (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Speech: Waco, TX, 1980 Oct 23 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Speech: Lynchberg College, 1992 Oct- 1993 Nov (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Speech: Library association, S.F., 1992 Jun (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Panel Discussion: AAUW, 1991 Nov 14 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Speech: Pacific Graduate School of Psychology, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Introduction of John Holland, 1980 Sep 1 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - "The Counseling Machine" speech, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Speech: Michigan coun. Assoc., 1996 Nov (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Speech: Auburn, Maine, 1996 Jun (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Virginia Counselors Assoc, 1995 Nov (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Speech: Univ. of Minn, 1995 May (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Speech: JFKU, 1995 Mar 11 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Speech: Ottawa, Canada, 1995 Jan (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Speech: Oregon, 1995 Feb (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Arkansas Coun. Ass'n, 1994 Nov (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Speech: JFK University, 1993 Jul (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Speech: Gov. St. University, 1993 May (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Speeches Ohio, 1993 Apr (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Speech: University of Minnesota, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Cognitive restructuring workshop (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Improving career dev. Theory (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Careers and personal beliefs (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Speech: changing career beliefs (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - CBI transparencies (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Theory as oversimplification (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Learning Theory of Career Counseling, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Learning Theory of Career Counseling, 1993-1995 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - CPP training workshop, 1991 Oct (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - CBI and tests in counseling, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 10)